杰森:在你的问题解决以前,
Jason: We're not going to get anywhere until we get past your denial of
我们是不会有什么进展的
the problem.
病人:我有什么问题?
Patient: What problem?
杰森:你也知道……
Jason: You see that's...
病人:难道你不觉得奇怪吗?怎么就只有你们这些人,才说我有问题,我老婆,
Patient: Isn't it odd the only people who say I have a problem are my wife,
我孩子,我上司,还有那些所谓的朋友.
my kids, my boss and those fair weather friends of mine.
杰森:这能说明什么?
Jason: Well, what does that tell you?
病人:说明他们都有问题.
Patient: That they got a problem.
杰森:不管怎样,下周再见!
Jason: Alright, see you next week, then.
病人:下周见,但还有见面的必要吗?
Patient: Sure, but I don't know why.
电话录音:麦琪,我是的比尔.
Answering Machine: Maggie, it's Bill, at the New York Times.
以你的履历来看,上我们这边做一些初级工作有点屈就你,所以……
I'm afraid you're over-qualified for an entry-level position.Thanks, anyway!
杰森:好希罕吗,你们也不就那样,有什么了不起的.
Jason: Who needs the New York Times, you're just a fish wrapper.
电话录音:我是十九频道新闻台的维尔娜,
Answering Machine: This is Velva at Channel 19 News, Mr.
斯维利维希先生想在明天下午三点约见你.
Sivelevich is confirming your interview at 3 pm tomorrow.
杰森:电视新闻,不错嘛,麦琪!
Jason: TV News, not bad Maggie.
电话录音:不好意思,我是维尔娜,
Answering Machine: This is Velva again, I'm sorry,
上头决定取消这次约见.
we have to cancel that interview.
杰森:笨蛋!难怪你们要做电视新闻.
Jason: Fools, that's why you're in TV News.
电话录音:麦琪,
Answering Machine: Maggie, this is Susan again.
我是苏珊.怎么老是不给老上司回个电话.
How about returning your old boss's calls?
有些事情你肯定很想知道.
I've got something you'll be very interested in.
杰森:嗨!面谈有进展吗?
Jason: Alriiiiight.Hey, how did the interview go?
麦琪:那个编辑整整跟我谈了一个小时.
Maggie: Well, the editor talked to me for a solid hour.
杰森:嗯,这证明你有希望了.这小子还挺有眼光的嘛!
Jason: Well, it sounds as if he liked what he heard.Sounds like a smart guy.
麦琪:他没打算雇用我.
Maggie: He didn't hire me.
杰森:原来还是个蠢才.
Jason: He's scum!
麦琪:杰森,如果今天有人再拒绝我的话,
Maggie: Jason, if I hear one more rejection today I'm going to scream.
我准会疯掉.有没有电话留言.
Any messages?
杰森:有啊,当然有.
Jason: Yeah, well, yes, yes.
麦琪:杰森,怎么了.
Maggie: Jason?
杰森:的比尔来过电话,你很符合他们的要求,
Jason: Bill, Bill called from the New York Times you came so close.
不过……噢,对了,十九频道的人事部也来过电话.
You came very very close.And uh, Channel 19 called.
麦琪:真的吗?他们有没有约见我?
Maggie: Oh did they confirm my interview?
杰森:可以说有,也可以说没有.
Jason: Yes and no.
麦琪:这从何说起?
Maggie: What?
杰森:嗯,后来他们又把约见取消了.
Jason: Well, they had to cancel.
麦琪:就是说他连见都没见我就把我给拒绝了.这倒好,
Maggie: So he's turning me down before he meets me.
大家都不用浪费时间了.
Nice, save everybody's time.
杰森:不是你想的那样,
Jason: No, no, no, he just got busy today.
只是他今天比较忙而已.他说要采访一个国会议员和脱衣女郎,
Something about a member of Congress and twin strippers.
具体情况我也不太清楚.
I didn't get the details.
麦琪:杰森,瞧你一肚子坏水.
Maggie: Jason you're so sick.
杰森:哼哼!不过现在我要告诉你一个好消息.
Jason: Yeah.Anyway, I saved the best for the last.
你可听好了,苏珊来过电话,说她有……
Wait 'til you here, Susan called and she has something...
麦琪:我十分感兴趣的东西,这事我知道,
Maggie: I'll be very interested in.
这周她天天来电话.
I know, she's been calling for a solid week.
杰森:你看好事不是说来就来了.
Jason: Well, you see this is a good thing.
麦琪:这算什么好事.
Maggie: No, it isn't.
杰森:不算好事!?这就是为什么我最后才讲这事.
Jason: No it isn't, no.That's why I saved it for the last.
麦琪:杰森,她是要我爬回报社,
Maggie: Jason she probably wants me to come crawling back to my old job,
低头向她认错,卑颜屈膝地向她道歉并承认我不该辞职.
hat in hand, virtually admitting it was a mistake to quit in the first place.
杰森:那好,最少要给十九频道打个电话,看能不能见个面.
Jason: Well at least call Channel 19, reset that interview.
麦琪:得了吧,杰森,这有必要吗?
Maggie: Oh Jason, what's the point?
杰森:亲爱的,我瞧你思想有点混乱.
Jason: Honey, you're just confused.
你觉得工作丢了,所以当时提出辞职无疑是个错误,
You're thinking here you are out of work,
感觉事业是在走下坡路.但是,
you made a mistake about quitting that job,
我们应该向前看,
you're feeling a little over the hill, but there's another hill Maggie,
麦琪,你的前程无量,
there's another, there's a huge hill,
所以目前这些琐事就别放在心上了.她要是能像我这样想就好了.
a mountain bigger when she thinks about that she'll feel better.
开萝尔:真是想不通,你居然要我一直蹲在车里,
Carol: I can't believe you wanted me to scrunch down in the floor of you
才肯带我回家.
car all the way home.
迈克:我也搞不明白,你怎么不按我说的去做.我得注意我的形象.
Mike: And I can't believe you wouldn't do it.I have an image to maintain.
本:得了吧,你想听听我的看法吗?
Ben: Yeah, did you hear me complaining?
开萝尔:我知道你要说什么,你不就是想让我用个袋子把头包起来吗?
Carol: Oh well, maybe I could just wear a bag over my head.
本:这注意不错,最好再掏两个洞好看东西.
Mike: That's not a bad idea, cut some little eyeholes.
杰森:孩子们!
Jason: Guys!
开萝尔:妈妈!
Carol: Mom!
杰森:你妈妈现在烦着呢,不要再去骚扰她了.
Jason: Mom has enough on her mind, don't give her any more head aches.
最近这几天她心情不大好,原因嘛,我想不说你们也知道.
She's been having a rough time these days and you all know why.
本:怎么了?
Ben: Why?
迈克:妈妈这几天到处在找工作,
Mike: Well, 'cause Mom's been bombing out on the job market and she feels
可老是碰壁.
like dog meat.
本:我怎么不知道.
Ben: I didn't know that.
开萝尔:本,你知道你刚才身处何方吗?
Carol: Ben, where have you been?
本:蹲在迈克的汽车里.妈妈为什么因为没了工作而不高兴?
Ben: On the floor of Mike's car.Why would Mom feel bad about not working?
迈克:你也觉得有问题,班尼?
Mike: You know, now that you mention it Benny I don't know why Mom went
我真不明白妈妈为什么非要去原来那地方工作,
back to work in the first place.
待在家里有什么不好?
I mean, she's got a pretty good job just hanging out here at home.
说实在的,我倒想娶个老婆来养我,
You know, I mean,
不用工作,而且吃穿不愁,
I wish some guy had come along and married me and pay my bills,
整天就是享福.
and buy me pretty dresses, you know what I mean.
开萝尔:你们两个蠢才,怎么一点也不替妈妈想想.
Carol: I should have known you two wouldn't understand.I mean how could you?
迈克:你聪明,
Mike: Hey look if you're so smart why don't you tell us why Mom needs
那你倒说说妈妈为什么非得去工作?
to get a job?
开萝尔:那你们听好了,工作不可或缺.
Carol: Okay, to feel vital.
工作就是为了贡献社会,
To be a productive, self-reliant clock in the machinery of society.
做整个社会有价值的一员,并在其中找到自我.
To forge her own identity.
迈克:我猜得没错,她的话就跟没说一样.
Mike: Just like I thought, she doesn't have a clue.
杰森:亲爱的,早点去休息吧?
Jason: Honey, you coming to bed soon?
麦琪:稍等,亲爱的,我得重新打一份简历.
Maggie: Oh, in a minute sweetheart I have to finish re-typing my resume.
杰森:我觉得以前的很好啊!
Jason: Well, it looked fine to me before.
麦琪:开玩笑!我现在才发现,简历就是问题所在.
Maggie: Are you kidding?It finally dawned on me what was wrong with it.
杰森:什么?
Jason: What?
麦琪:很明显,傻瓜都能看得出来.
Maggie: Well, it's obvious.Any fool can see it.
杰森:但我没觉得呀!
Jason: I don't see it.
麦琪:我的名字,看到没,字母全大写了.
Maggie: My name.It's in all capital letters.
杰森:那又如何?
Jason: So?
麦琪:难道你不觉得这有点自大吗?
Maggie: Well don't you think that's kind of self-important?
杰森:现在已经十二点半了,明天早晨等你脑子精神好一点的时候再改,
Jason: It's twelve thirty in the morning maybe you should do this when
你看如何?.亲爱的,这样下去可不行,
you're thinking a little more clearly.
说句老实话,这三周,
Not that you're not now, it's just Honey, I can't do it.
我一直是小心翼翼,如履薄冰,
I've been walking on eggs around here for three weeks now and it's just
生怕你不高兴.为了名字的大写,就要把简历重打一遍,
not working.I gotta be honest with you,
这简直是没事找事!明白吗?
changing your resume because your name is in capitals is nuts!There I said it.
麦琪:那好,你说为什么人家不想雇用我?
Maggie: Well, why do you think I haven't been hired?
杰森:这个问题提的好,麦琪.
Jason: Well now that's an excellent question Maggie.
这是问题的关键所在,
That's the essential question here I think our time would be very
要是能够好好的仔细想想,
productively spent if we just thought about that for a while and discussed
各方面的原因原因都能考虑进来,我们就会解决这个难题.
all the possible reasons.
麦琪:行间距改成三倍的或许会好点.
Maggie: Maybe I should triple space this.
杰森:问题不在这,亲爱的,
Jason: No, no, no, honey, forget the typing!Now deal with the question here.
事情跟打字没关系!问题是,你认为问什么别人不雇用你?
Why do you think you haven't been hired?
麦琪:或许有些男的对我这个聪明性感的金发美女有点嫉妒.
Maggie: Possibly some men are intimidated by a talented, sexy blonde.
杰森:你真这么想.
Jason: Do you believe that?
麦琪:除此之外,还有别的解释吗?
Maggie: I'd like to.
杰森:我觉得你的判断有问题.
Jason: I think you've losing your perspective.
麦琪:不是,我只是觉得有点手足无措.我只想找份工作而已.
Maggie: No I'm losing my mind.All I want is a job where I feel needed.
本:开萝尔说得没错,事情怎么会这样呢?
Ben: Carol was right!How could that be?
麦琪:我一会就完成,行吗?
Maggie: Look, I'll be up in a few minutes, okay?
杰森:好.
Jason: Ok.
麦琪:我爱你!
Maggie: I love you.
杰森:我也爱你.
Jason: Love you too.
本:妈妈?
Ben: Mom?
麦琪:班尼,你想干什么?
Maggie: Benny, what are you doing up?
本:我很担心你!!
Ben: I was worried about you.
麦琪:真的吗?
Maggie: Oh, you were?
本:妈妈,我只是想告诉你,
Ben: Mom, I just want you to know that I'll love you even if no one
即使全世界都没人雇你工作,我都会一如既往的爱你.
on earth will hire you.
麦琪:谢谢你,本杰明.
Maggie: Why thank you, Benjamin.
本:妈妈,你不一定非得去工作不可.
Ben: Mom you don't need a job to feel good,
我的意思是,我不也没工作吗,照样过得很开心.
I mean I've never had a job and I feel great.
麦琪:这我倒从来没想过.
Maggie: You know, I've never looked at it that way.
本:你瞧,我吃饭,看电视,
Ben: You should, I mean, I eat, I watch TV, I do my homework.
做功课,有时连功课也不做,多么消遥自在!!
Sometimes I don't even do my homework.
麦琪:嗯,你的主意不错嘛!
Maggie: Sounds very nice.
本:当然,那你还为没工作不开心吗?
Ben: It is.So, are you done worrying now?
麦琪:本,你的话对我帮助很大,也很有启发.
Maggie: Well, let's put it this way, Ben.I'm very glad we had this talk.
本:我们一起吃块馅饼你会更高兴的.
Ben: You know, you'd feel even better if we split a wedge of pie.
麦琪:还好!迈克,拿着你的早点.
Maggie: Not bad.Here's your breakfast Michael.
迈克:让我拿这个干吗?
Mike: What am I supposed to do with this?
麦琪:当然是吃喽!
Maggie: Eat it.
迈克:我没听错吧?
Mike: Pardon me?
麦琪:当早点吃了它!坐下来慢慢享用.
Maggie: Eat, sit.Enjoy.
迈克:热乎乎的早点,这主意真是没得说!
Mike: Oh, hot breakfast.What an interesting idea.
开萝尔:早上好!
Carol: Morning!
麦琪:你打算怎么吃来着,开萝尔?煎一面,还是两面都煎?
Maggie: How you want them Carol, scrambled, over easy, or sunny side up?
开萝尔:不用,妈妈,喝点果汁就行.
Carol: Oh, I usually just have juice.
麦琪:以后可不行!!
Maggie: Not anymore.
开萝尔:到底怎么了?
Carol: What's going on?
迈克:妈妈有点反常,刚才还给我果酱当早点来着.
Mike: Oh she's lost her mind, pass the syrup.
本:早上好!!
Ben: Morning!
麦琪:嗨,班尼,要煎饼还是鸡蛋?香肠还是火腿?
Maggie: Hi Benny, pancakes or eggs?Sausage or ham?
本:都要!!
Ben: Sure!
杰森:早上好!
Jason: Morning.
麦琪:大家都到齐了,我有一件事情要宣布,
Maggie: And now that we're all together.I have an announcement to make.
昨晚有一位非常聪明的人,给了我很大启发,
I had an enlightening talk last night with a very wise man.
他让我认识到,
And he helped me realize that I've put too much importance on this job hunt,
我对寻找工作看得太重要了,因而使我忽视了更为重要的东西.
and it's getting in the way of more important things.
所以我现在决定把我关心的重点,转移到家里来.
So I've decided to just be happy taking care of the family I love.
迈克:硬塞给我这么多吃的??
Mike: You got any more flap jacks?
开萝尔:真是蠢才!
Carol: You're a pig.
杰森:亲爱的,我很高兴你能跟那位你说得那个睿智之人促膝谈心,
Jason: Honey, I'm so glad you had that talk with that very wise man.
他很爱你的!
And he loves you very much.
本:即使你没给他吃馅饼,他仍然爱你.
Ben: Yeah, even if you didn't give him a piece of pie.
杰森:嗯>
Jason: Huh?
麦琪:所以,为了整理好房子,我就列了一份家务分配表,
Maggie: So let's get this house in order.
每个人都得切实执行各项任务,大家好久都没做家务了,应该好好锻炼一下了.
I've got a list here of chores that have been neglected for a very long time.
迈克:妈妈,你不是在开玩笑吧?
Mike: This is some kind of joke, right?
麦琪:当然不是,迈克,如果我要呆在家里,那我就得做好各项工作!
Maggie: No, Mike, if I'm going to be home I'm going to do a good job.
开萝尔:哪个睿智之人昨晚跟妈妈有过促膝交谈.
Carol: Ok, who's the wise guy who spoke to Mom last night.
杰森:你妈妈是对的,每个人都得完成自己的份内工作.
Jason: Well your Mom's right.Everyone has to pull their own weight.
麦琪:谢谢你,亲爱的.
Maggie: Well thank you sweetheart, I rented you a Rota tiller.
我给你租了一台割草机,今天下午就送到.
It'll be delivered this afternoon.
杰森:嗯,不错!!
Jason: Oh boy.
麦琪:校车开过来了,孩子们都快去上学吧,
Maggie: Oh that's your bus, Ben.Mike, Carol, you should go, you'll be late.
别忘了带着午饭.
Don't forget your lunches.
迈克:妈妈,我就今天带午饭,明天免谈!!
Mike: Mom, I'm only going to be gone for one day.
病人:我发言到一半,朝台上一看,陪审团团长已经睡着了,
Patient: So, in the middle of my summation I look up and the jury foreman
这种事都会发生.医生,医生,
is asleep.Can you imagine?Doctor?Doctor!
我算明白了,不光是陪审团觉得我的发言无聊,原来你也是.
Well, I guess juries are not the only people who find me boring.
杰森:这是我的不对,不好意思!我妻子硬逼着我吃了那么多早饭,
Jason: This was completely unprofessional, I'm very sorry, I had a very big,
火腿蛋,烙饼,还有其他好多东西.
an enormous breakfast that I didn't even wanted, with sausages,
总之,实在,
I had pancakes.Anyway, I'm sorry, I'll see you next week and uh,
不好意思!那我们下星期再见了,今天的诊费就不必了.
no charge for this session obviously.
病人:莫非你还好意思要.
Patient: Obviously.
杰森:瞧您说到哪里去了.
Jason: Oh no.
麦琪:今天心情很不好,别来烦我!
Maggie: Oh, you spoiled the surprise!
杰森:麦琪,我们得坐下来好好谈谈.
Jason: Maggie, we have to have a calm, rational, talk.
麦琪:好啊!
Maggie: Ok.
麦琪:找份工作!!
Jason: Get a job!
麦琪:你说什么?
Maggie: What?
杰森:对不起,当我没说,行吗?
Jason: I'm sorry, it's my stomach talking, not my head.
麦琪:你是不是觉得我的厨艺太差了?
Maggie: You don't like my cape con medley?
杰森:不是你想到那样!原因是我认为你呆在家里,没上班的时候,那么快乐.
Jason: No it's just that, I really don't think that you're nearly happy being at
home as you seem to be
麦琪:杰森,呆在家里我当然感到很开心.瞧见没,光奶酪我就做了三样.
Maggie: Oh, of course I'm happy Jason, well look!Three different cheeses.
杰森:我很后悔你听了我昨晚的意见.
Jason: I'm very flattered that you took my advice last night.
麦琪:不是你的意见,而是本的意见给了我很大的启发.
Maggie: Well, no, no, no, I didn't take your advice, I took Ben's.
杰森:本的意见?那个睿智之人居然是本?
Jason: Ben's?The very wise man was Ben?
麦琪:他的话很有道理,要想快乐,
Maggie: Well he made a lot of sense,
并不是非工作不可.
he said I didn't need a job to be happy.
杰森:他能知道什么叫工作?麦琪,
Jason: Oh what does he know about jobs, Maggie?
他才11岁而已,一天也没有工作过!!
He's eleven years old, he's never worked a day in his life.
麦琪:不过,我倒觉得他的看法很合我意!
Maggie: Well that was his point.
他说我就是哪儿都找不到工作,他还是很爱我,
You know he's just made it easier for me to accept the fact that there
听了这话,我才有了今天的决定.
was simply no jobs out there for me.
杰森:亲爱的,你之所以找不到工作,就是因为你太为自己而自豪.
Jason: Honey, the only think keeping you out of the job market is pride.
麦琪:你说什么?
Maggie: What?
杰森:自豪感,亲爱的!!有份工作正等着你呢!!
Jason: Pride, honey!There is a job out there for you.
麦琪:杰森,每个约见我都去了,结果你也知道.
Maggie: Jason I followed up on every single lead.
杰森:可你从来没给苏珊回过电话??
Jason: Except one.How many times has Susan called?
麦琪:你的意思是让我回到原来的单位.
Maggie: Yeah, about my old job.
杰森:嗯,没错!原来那份工作不是挺好嘛!
Jason: Right, what was wrong with your old job.
麦琪:呃,听我说行不行?
Maggie: Well, I'll tell you, it...
杰森:洗耳恭听!
Jason: I'm waiting.
麦琪:嗨!这个……
Maggie: Well, it uh.
杰森:你就承认了吧,你很喜欢原来的工作,
Jason: Admit it!Honey, you loved your old job,
三年来,你一直热爱着那份工作.
and you found it very rewarding for three years.
麦琪:没错,但是……
Maggie: Yeah, but...
杰森:你也很擅长此道,麦琪.
Jason: And you were good at it, Maggie.
麦琪:我工作的确很出色,真的吗?
Maggie: I was pretty good at it, wasn't I?
杰森:那当然!原来那份工作在等你,
Jason: You still are.Come on, it's sitting there waiting for you.
那你还犹豫什么?
What's stopping you?
麦琪:不知道小本怎么想?
Maggie: Gee, I wonder what little Ben would advise.
麦琪:一切如常,我又回来啦.
Maggie: Hello old desk, hello old chair.Hi.I'm back.
苏珊:麦琪!
Susan: Maggie!
麦琪:苏珊,我的自尊心也太强了,
Maggie: Well Susan, I figured to heck with my pride I owe it to you to
我愿意来这儿听听你的说法,
hear what you have to say but if you feel it's something I'd want then
不过那个确实是我的确很需要,
it's good enough for me and you know how I hate to dicker, so,
我也不想再多费唇舌,我要了……
I'll take it.
苏珊:那好,这就是.
Susan: You got it.Here.
麦琪:什么?这是……
Maggie: What?
苏珊:这都是你原来办公桌里面的各项物品,现在卡罗琳要在那工作,
Susan: You left this in your desk.
她说这些东西她用不着,嚷嚷着要把扔掉.
Actually Carinne's desk now,
但我想这些得算是你的纪念品,
she said it was junk and just wanted to toss it but I said no,
所以就一直留着,等你来拿.
these are Maggie's memories.
麦琪:这些天你电话不断就是为了把这些东西还给我?
Maggie: You mean what you've been calling me about all week is this junk?
迈克:都怪你让妈妈留在家里,害得我们好苦!
Mike: The sooner I get done with Mom's chores, the sooner I'm outta here.
本:早知如此,我也不会去给妈妈鼓劲了!
Ben: I wouldn't have cheered Mom up if I would've known it would lead to this.
迈克:说得倒好听!
Mike: Perfect.Hey!
本:我又不是故意的!
Ben: Sorry!
迈克:现在道歉有什么用!
Mike: Oh, you're sorry.That makes it okay?
开萝尔:本!
Carol: Ben!I need your Ah!
是谁把这桶肥料放在路中间?!
Who left the fertilizer right in the middle of the walk way?
本:要我给你冲一下吗?
Ben: Want me to hose you off?
开萝尔:你还说!!
Carol: I'll hose you off!
迈克:这是什么事啊!
Mike: This whole situation stinks.
本:跟我无关.
Ben: Not the situation.
迈克:我们得给妈妈找份工作,越快越好.
Mike: Guys, we have to get Mom a job, fast.
开萝尔:志愿工作也行.
Carol: Volunteer work, anything.
迈克:嘘-嘘-嘘!妈妈回来啦!
Mike: Shhh, here she comes.
开萝尔:妈妈,回来啦!
Carol: Hi Mom!
迈克:妈妈,怎么样?
Mike: Yo, Mom!
麦琪:你们好啊,孩子们!
Maggie: Hi.
杰森:亲爱的,工作搞定了?
Jason: Honey, back already?
麦琪:没有,
Maggie: Oh Jason, they didn't want me.
杰森!
They just wanted me to pick up what was left of my career and it all
他们不是想要我回去工作,只是要我把以前的东西拿回来而已,
fit in a little box,
这些垃圾丢到阁楼的废物堆倒挺合适的.
which I'm going to put in the attic with the other junk.
杰森:没事,别担心,宝贝.
Jason: It's ok, baby.
麦琪:我不是小孩子,我成年了,是大人!
Maggie: Oh, I am not a baby, I'm a grown up.Oh, Jason.
杰森,管他什么工作不工作呢,统统跟我没关系.
Well, who needs a stupid job anyway?Not me.
我就想好好呆在家里,全心全意的做个家庭主妇.
I can be very happy being the best wife and mother in the entire state
做整个纽约州最好的,全世界最好的,甚至整个宇宙最好的家庭主妇.
of New York.Maybe the world.Maybe, maybe the universe.
杰森:没事,没事,亲爱的,
Jason: Baby stop, honey, come on, you don't have to be super Mom.
别做什么超级母亲,还有什么超级记者,
You don't have to be super reporter, you don't have to be super anything.
或别的什么.你就做你自己好了,我就是喜欢你现在这个样子.
You just have to be Maggie.Who I happen to love very much by the way.
麦琪:你对我很失望.
Maggie: So you're not disappointed in me.
杰森:当然没有,如果你觉得呆在家里很高兴,我也会很高兴的.
Jason: Of course not, hey, if you're happy being at home then I'm happy.
麦琪:可我看你的样子并不是很高兴.
Maggie: You don't seem happy.
杰森:我当然很高兴.
Jason: I'm happy.
麦琪:你没有.
Maggie: You're not.
杰森:我有!
Jason: I am!
麦琪:你没有!
Maggie: You're not.
杰森:我有!
Jason: I am!
麦琪:好吧,我相信你.
Maggie: Ok, I believe you.
杰森:那好!
Jason: Ok.
麦琪:行,那我就好好呆在家里!
Maggie: Fine.So, home it is then.
杰森:这样很好啊!
Jason: Yes.
麦琪:那就这样!
Maggie: It's settled then.
杰森:还能怎样?!
Jason: Good.
麦琪:现在我觉得很开心.
Maggie: And I'm happy, too.
杰森:那就好.
Jason: Good.
麦琪:你真的没对我失望吗?
Maggie: Are you sure you're not disappointed in me?
杰森:那当然!!
Jason: Absolutely.
麦琪:那就好!
Maggie: Good.
杰森:不过,要是害怕再被人家回绝,
Jason: Fine.The only way I'd be disappointed in you is if you were choosing
你才决定留在家里,那我就会感到很失望.
home because you were afraid of more rejection.
麦琪:嗯!!
Maggie: Uh huh.
杰森:既然情况不是这样,所以我说好极了.
Jason: But since that isn't the case here then I say bully.
要是你真的想从工作当中,
I mean, unless you want the increased self-esteem that comes with having
来体现自我价值,
your own career then I say forget sending the resume, forget the interviews,
那就应该忘掉履历表,忘掉什么面谈,
especially the one with Channel 19 in forty-five minutes.
特别是要忘掉十九频道新闻台的面谈,应该下决心呆在家里,
Enjoy your decision to stay at home.
应该真正陶醉的在家庭天伦之乐的幸福中.
Wallow in the warmth of your family, clinging unto your bosom.
麦琪:他还是对我很失望.
Maggie: He is disappointed in me.
本:妈妈?
Ben: Mom?
麦琪:怎么了,本?
Maggie: Yes, Ben?
本:我想跟您谈谈.
Ben: I'd like to talk.
妈妈,记得昨天晚上我说过的话吗?
Mom you remember everything I said last night about you not needing a
就是不工作呆在家里也没什么大不了的那句话!
job to feel good?
麦琪:当然记得.
Maggie: Uh huh.
本:其实那些话都是骗你的.妈妈,你先忙,我要去做家务了.
Ben: It was a total lie.Thank you for your time.
女士:谢谢,是的,
Lady: Thank you, yes ma'am, we're all communists here at News 19.
夫人,我们十九频道全是共产党,所以才会播出这种新闻,
Uh huh, that's why the news comes out like that.
对,谢谢你的意见.
Yeah, uh huh, thank you for calling.
麦琪:打扰一下!我想见见斯维利维希先生.
Maggie: Excuse me, I'm here to see Mr.Sivlevich.
如果他太忙的话,我可以先离开.谁想老是被人拒绝.
But if he's busy that's fine, I'll just leave.Who needs more rejection?
女士:您说什么?
Lady: Pardon?
麦琪:没什么,我等等.
Maggie: No.I'll wait.
女士:好吧,那您先等等,
Lady: Okay.Just get comfortable and we'll be with you in the teeniest
我去看看.请叫保安过来一下.
of moments.Security, please.
麦琪:这件事久拖不决,
Maggie: I swear, I've been back and forth on this so many times I don't
实在不能再等下去了.
know what I want anymore.
女士:新闻室,快点!
Lady: News room, hurry.
麦琪:其实,我自己也不知道我想要什么.
Maggie: No, I do know what I want.
女士:真的?
Lady: You do?
麦琪:得了吧,我知道自己是谁.
Maggie: Heck, I know who I am.
女士:你到底是谁?
Lady: Who the hell are you?
麦琪:噢,对不起,我是莎娜·斯卡.
Maggie: Oh, I'm sorry, I'm Shauna Scaw!
女士:嗯,你的名字跟我们女主播的名字完全一样.
Lady: Well, you have the very same name as our anchor woman.
麦琪:不是,我叫麦琪·西维尔.
Maggie: No no no, I'm Maggie Seaver.
女士:噢,原来如此.您是参加面试的.
Lady: Oh, well, you're not a nut, you have an appointment.
警察:不许动!
Police: Freeze!
女士:只是演习而已.这边请,斯维利维希先生,麦琪·西维尔来了.
Lady: Just testing.Right this way.Mr.Sivlevich, Maggie Seaver.
麦琪:斯维利维希先生,非常感谢您给我机会.
Maggie: Mr.Sivlevich, thank you.
斯维利维希先生:你以前做过电视新闻没?
Mr.Sivlevich: Have you ever worked in a TV news before?
麦琪:没有!
Maggie: No.
斯维利维希先生:广播呢?
Mr.Sivelevich: Radio?
麦琪:也没有!
Maggie: Afraid not.
斯维利维希先生:相关经验呢?
Mr.Sivlevich: Broadcast experience?
麦琪:一点点.
Maggie: Zilch.
斯维利维希先生:这倒是条大新闻.开个玩笑!!
Mr.Sivelevich: You sound like anchor material.Just a little news record joke.
斯维利维希先生:开玩笑?你拿我开玩笑?
Maggie: A joke?You're making a joke?
斯维利维希先生:难道你不觉得好笑吗?
Mr.Sivelevich: You didn't find it amusing?
麦琪:这一点都不好笑.
Maggie: Well, not particularly.And you know why?
你知道为什么吗?我已经被拒绝了27次了,
I have just gone through 27 turndowns for job interviews.
被人开了15次玩笑.
It stopped being amusing around 15.
斯维利维希先生:怎么,你要去哪?
Mr.Sivelevich: Where are you going?
麦琪:好吧,你是真的要跟我面谈一下了?
Maggie: Ok, you really want to go through this job interview?
先谈谈我的简历吧,我在新闻周刊做过两年研究工作,
Let's start with my resume.You'll see two years as a researcher at Newsweek.
做过14年家庭主妇,
Fourteen years as a house wife and three years at a neighborhood paper
在一家报社干了三年,我知道你会说我并不适合电视新闻.
and you're going say she's not ready for TV.
斯维利维希先生:你想要这份工作吗?
Mr.Sivlevich: Excuse me, you are trying to get this job right?
麦琪:当然想要,不过我知道你要么说我难以胜任,
Maggie: Sure, but if I'm not under-qualified then I am over-qualified
要么说我是大材小用,要么我年龄太大,
or I'm too old, or my name is all in capital letters.
要么指摘我的名字用了大写.老实告诉你,
But you know what Mr.
斯维利维希先生,
Sivlevich, it doesn't matter because somebody will hire me.
这一切我都他妈的不在乎,总会有人雇我,
I know that now,
我相信自己,我们全家上下都对我很有信心.
I learned that from my family but you probably don't give a hoot about
不过对你说了也白说,再见!
them either.Good day!
斯维利维希先生:等等,我决定雇你了.
Mr.Sivlevich: Wait a minute!I get my chance to hire you!
你的文章我拜读过,我觉得很不错,这也是为什么要雇你的原因所在.
I read your stuff, I like it, that's why you're here, that's how it works.
麦琪:嗯,那你快说.
Maggie: Ok, make it quick.
斯维利维希先生:那你听着,
Mr.Sivlevich: Ok, now here's the deal.
我们想找个人专门负责撰写新闻稿,原因是原来那位谋到一份更好的差事.
I got this writing job open because the guy that had it before quit to
所以,
go to a bigger market.
我想找个会写新闻稿的,能吃苦耐劳,
I need someone who knows who they are, who'll do a good job,
同时肯多花心思的撰稿人.
and who will stick around here for a while.
莎娜·斯卡需要有人替她写新闻稿,这样她就不至于在信口开河了,
Shauna Small needs somebody good writing for her so that she doesn't,
明白我的意思吗?
god forbid, start ad-libbing again.Follow me?
麦琪:不是很了解.
Maggie: Not really, see
斯维利维希先生:我们为长岛做新闻,
Mr.Sivelevich: Now we do local news for Long Island,
还得过六次奖?
we have won six awards by the way.
下个月莎娜·斯卡可能就要生孩子,所以现在趁早找个能写稿子的,
And if all Shauna has her baby next month during ratings sweep the way
到时候我们就不会措手不及了,
she's supposed to we can pick up a couple of points and I won't have to
这下明白了吗?
jerk my kid out of USC.What do you think?
面积:嗯,算无遗策!!
Maggie: I hear it's a great school.
斯维利维希先生:那工作呢?
Mr.Sivelevich: About the job?
麦琪:很不错!
Maggie: It sounds very exciting.
斯维利维希先生:那你想不想干这份工作?
Mr.Sivelevich: Do you want the job or not?
麦琪:当然!
Maggie: Well, of course I do.
斯维利维希先生:嗯,愿我们合作愉快!
Mr.Sivelevich: Well, you're hired.
麦琪:好的.
Maggie: Ok.
斯维利维希先生:你先出去让希尔玛带你熟悉一下.
Mr.Sivelevich: Ok, now get out of here and have Thelma show you around.
麦琪:好的!我被雇用了?
Maggie: Fine!I'm what?
斯维利维希先生:对没错!现在起你为我们工作,我们支付工资.
Mr.Sivelevich: Hired.You know, you work for us.We pay you.Starting now.
麦琪:你决定雇用我了?
Maggie: You mean you, you want me?
斯维利维希先生:当然,诚心诚意!!怎么……
Mr.Sivelevich: Oh to the core of my very soul!Alright!Now what do you think?
麦琪:噢,女主播要生了!!
Maggie: Oh gosh, I think Oh!I think, your anchor woman just went into labor!
斯维利维希先生:不会吧!!
Mr.Sivelevich: She looks good.
迈克:有谁听说过在秋天却搞春季大扫除?
Mike: Who the heck ever heard of spring-cleaning in the fall?
开萝尔:世界的有的地方现在就是春季.
Carol: Well, in some parts of the world it is spring.
迈克:那你是不是很想去那个地方?
Mike: Well, why don't you find out where and go there?
杰森:晚饭时间快到了,大家洗洗准备吃饭.
Jason: Come on, you guys can wash up for dinner now.
本:如果妈妈找到了新工作,我们要不要出去庆贺一下.
Ben: We're probably going out to celebrate Mom's new job.
杰森:如果事与愿违,
Jason: Well that would be nice Ben, but we gotta let her know,
那我们就对她说呆在家里也很不错,
even if it didn't work out,
明白吗?
that we're behind her whether she's working or not working, right?
本:您好,我是本·西维尔,请问有事吗?嗨,妈妈,怎么样?好的,再见!
Ben: Hello, Ben Seaver, how may I help you?Mom, how did it?Ok, bye.
杰森:你妈妈怎么说,本?
Jason: What'd she say Ben?
本:妈妈让我们快点打开电视收看十九频道.
Ben: She says she wants us to turn on Channel 19 immediately.
电视节目:大扫除请用巴特勒牌洗涤剂.
TV: So far all your house cleaning needs it's Butler in a Bucket.
迈克:嘿,那是妈妈,真有意思.
Mike: Oh funny, Mom, really funny.
杰森:她说什么来着?
Jason: What else did she say?
麦琪:今天十九频道出了一件很有意思的新闻.新闻节目女主播刚刚生下一个非常可爱的女儿.
Maggie on TV: Today Channel 19 experienced some growing pains of its own.
各位观众,
Anchorwoman Shauna Small gave birth late this afternoon to a bouncy baby
请看直播,
girl which many of you may have seen live right here on News 19 and oh,
对不起,我在跟大家开玩笑而已.
we are very sorry about that.
杰森:嗨!你妈妈现在上电视了.
Jason: She got a job on the air.
麦琪:各位观众我是新的女主播,负责为十九频道撰写新闻稿.
Maggie on TV: And as you may have noticed I'm a new addition, too.
因为莎娜产假,
Um, I've just joined News 19 as a news writer but while Shauna's on maternity
克劳兹博士在编辑稿件,理查德负责播送气象预报,
leave Dr.Claus is anchoring, Ricardo's doing the weather, and somehow,
所以就让我主持新闻节目.不过莎娜不久就会重新与大家见面,
I've ended up on the air.
因为家庭需要她但是工作更需要她.对此大家应该很认同我的观点,
But Shauna will be back because she's needed just as much here as she
不管你的家庭有多么完美幸福.
is at home and that's something that we all need to hear once in a while
十九频道新闻台,麦琪·马龙.
even if we do have the best family on earth.For News 19, I'm Maggie Malone.
迈克:妈妈上电视了,棒极了!
杰森:改名了,麦琪·马龙!!
00:22:45,200
Mike: Is this great or what? Jason: It's my Maggie.Malone?